A Guide to the Emma Dorothy Southworth Collection
University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #8315-a
Emma Dorothy Southworth Collection 1852-1894
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
8315-a
8 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Purchase [ 1967 Dec 1 ] 1968 Jan 19
Item Listing
- Quotations
  - Quotation beginning, "Trust first in God.. .", 1858 Mar 4; AQS, 1 p.
  - Quotation beginning, "Let us ask ourselves at night.. .", n. d.; AQS, 1 p.
- Letters
  - Emma Dorothy Southworth to [Abraham Hart], 1853 Jan 29; ALS, 1 p.
    [Sends him two stories with "good and practical moral" to be included in a volume; includes a dedication; asks for 2 copies for herself; requests to see a proof sheet of the engravings.]
  - Emma Dorothy Southworth to "My Precious Friend", 1894 Jun 11; ALS, 4 p.
    [Inquires about Grace Greenwood to whom she has recently written but has not received a reply from; gives a description of Greenwood the way she was in 1850; wonders if she has offended Greenwood with her letter; asks correspondent to look for Greenwood in the city and to let her know; invites correspondent to visit her now, when the countryside is so beautiful.]
  - Emma Dorothy Southworth to [Charles Jacobs] Peterson, Sunday; ALS, 1 p.
    [Promises him a double amount of copy for the next day; mentions the bad notices her piece
    Mark
    got from the English critics.]
  - Emma Dorothy Southworth to "My Dear Young Friend", [1890 Nov 23]; ALS, 2 p.
    [Thanks him for his letter and an enclosed newspaper clipping, which was provided by one of his friends; appreciates that he rose to her defense when she was so outrageously libeled; promises him a copy once her final reply is finished.]
  - Emma Dorothy Southworth to [publisher ?], last page, [1892 Dec 16]; ALS, 1 p.
    [Pleads with correspondent not to publish anything about her childhood without her endorsement when he publishes a piece about her in honor of her 73rd birthday.]
- Miscellaneous
  - Printed article, "Mrs. Emma D. E. N. Southworth at Prospect Cottage," by Charles Warren Stoddard in National Magazine, 1905 May; Article, 12 p.